const quizQuestions9en =[{
    question:"In MIG/MAG welding with 1.0 mm wire, these are parameter adjustments that ensure a long arc and spray-type transfer:",
    answers: ["voltage range 25-35 V and wire feed speed from 8 to 10 m/min;",
    "voltage range 20-25 V and wire feed speed from 8 to 10 m/min;",
    "voltage range 25-38 V and wire feed speed from 5 to 7 m/min;",
    "voltage range 17-25 V and wire feed speed from 8 to 10 m/min;"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which welding process uses the highest heat input?",
    answers: ["Submerged arc welding.",
    "Ultrasonic welding.",
    "Electroslag welding.",
    "Electron beam welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which ISO code of these welding processes is wrong:",
    answers: ["GMAW, MIG, 131",
    "GMAW, MAG, 135",
    "GTAW, TIG, 140",
    "SMAW, MMA, 111"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is a function of the flux used in oxyfuel gas welding?",
    answers: ["To protect the weld pool.",
    "To increase the weld pool temperature.",
    "To remove oxides from the base metal surface.",
    "To increase the penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The basicity index of a submerged arc welding (SAW) flux represents:",
    answers: ["the ratio of basic components to acidic components in the flux;",
    "the percentage of basic components content;",
    "a degree of Mn and Si transfer from the flux;",
    "the ratio of acidic to basic components in the flux."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What would happen with the behaviour of the MIG/MAG welding process if a Constant Current power source is used?",
    answers: ["The arc striking would be more reliable but the arc length would not be maintained constant.",
    "Both, the arc striking and the arc length self-adjustment would worsen.",
    "The electrode fusion rate would be lower because of a lower welding current.",
    "The arc length self-adjustment would worsen but the penetration would be maintained more constant."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In TIG welding a carbon steel, the used shielding gas is:",
    answers: ["an Argon+CO2 mixture;",
    "an inert gas;",
    "an active gas;",
    "an Argon+O2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When MIG/MAG welding thin plates, the short-circuiting metal transfer mode is recommended because:",
    answers: ["the welding pool is of small dimensions and the heat transferred to the weld pool is low;",
    "a stream of discrete droplets accelerated by arc forces is directed towards the weld pool;",
    "the gravitational force is dominant facilitating the metal droplet transfer;",
    "a low voltage, even with high current (typical for this metal transfer mode) allows avoiding a burn-through."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The maximum number of times an electrode can be re-dried is limited because:",
    answers: ["redrying may deteriorate the electrode core metal mechanical properties;",
    "the electrode coating becomes too dry and will be prone to absorbing moisture much more readily;",
    "during redrying the electrode coating loses alloying elements;",
    "each redrying deteriorates the electrode coating mechanical strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which one of the following is a characteristic of the SAW process?",
    answers: ["Even though the electric arc is not visible, protective equipment such as a welding helmet and a leather apron are necessary.",
    "Can be done in any welding position.",
    "According to the manufacturing process, the main types of flux are: fused fluxes e agglomerated fluxes.",
    "SAW is a low deposition rate process which is generally used to weld thin sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which welding process uses the highest heat input?",
    answers: ["Submerged arc welding.",
    "Ultrasonic welding.",
    "Electroslag welding.",
    "Electron beam welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of cutting methods provides the narrowest cut?",
    answers: ["Carbon arc cutting.",
    "Plasma arc cutting.",
    "Laser beam cutting.",
    "Oxyfuel gas cutting."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which factor is not of great importance for a correct choice of gas in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Type and thickness of the metal to be welded.",
    "Metal transfer mode.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Welding cost."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"How to identify a low hydrogen electrode?",
    answers: ["By the classification code printed on the electrode.",
    "By the electrode performance.",
    "By the visual appearance of the slag.",
    "By the visual appearance of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"How should low hydrogen electrodes be stored?",
    answers: ["Inside a steel cabinet, properly labelled and ready for distribution.",
    "In its original and sealed packaging.",
    "Inside a steel cabinet with the temperature kept below 20 oC.",
    "Inside a holding oven at a temperature above 200 oC."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"How should low hydrogen electrodes be stored?",
    answers: ["Inside a steel cabinet, properly labelled and ready for distribution.",
    "In a holding oven at a temperature that guarantees low humidity.",
    "Inside a steel cabinet with the temperature kept below 20 oC.",
    "Inside a holding oven at a temperature above 200 oC."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct statement regarding the selection of a shielding gas in TIG welding carbon steel.",
    answers: ["Both inert and oxidizing gas mixtures can be used, in the same way as in MIG/MAG welding.",
    "In TIG welding, for any base material, only inert gases or their mixtures are used.",
    "Ar-O2 mixtures can be used if you need a better protection for the tungsten electrode.",
    "Ar+CO2 mixtures can be used to increase penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Covered Electrode welding process (SMAW/MMA).",
    answers: ["To compensate for variations in arc length (and, therefore, in arc voltage), the power sources used in this process are of the Constant Voltage type.",
    "Alternate or direct current can be used. When direct current is used, the polarity can be either positive (most common) or negative electrode.",
    "The protection of the weld pool and droplets is always achieved by the slag.",
    "The main reason for a low deposition rate of this process is because the electrode feeding is not continuous."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the purposes of preheating in welding?",
    answers: ["To increase welding efficiency.",
    "To increase the deposition rate.",
    "To reduce the presence of moisture on the workpiece.",
    "To avoid porosity in the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative, regarding the TIG welding process.",
    answers: ["The electrode negative polarity (DCEN) is applied when welding carbon and stainless steels.",
    "The electrode positive polarity (DCEP) is applied for welding aluminium.",
    "Alternating current is never used in the TIG welding process.",
    "The electrode sharpening angle should be smaller as the welding current increases."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Covered electrodes are classified according to:",
    answers: ["the destination (to weld carbon steels, low alloy steels, aluminium and its alloys, etc.);",
    "the recommended welding position (flat, overhead, etc.);",
    "a recommended current type (alternating current, direct current with electrode positive or direct current electrode negative polarity).",
    "the diameter of their core wire (1.6 mm, 2.0 mm, 2.5 mm and so on)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Covered electrodes are classified according to:",
    answers: ["the recommended welding position (flat, overhead, etc.);",
    "the type of coating (basic, rutile, etc.);",
    "a recommended current type (alternating current, direct current with electrode positive or direct current electrode negative polarity).",
    "the diameter of their core wire (1.6 mm, 2.0 mm, 2.5 mm and so on)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why in TIG welding the arc must be opened without touching the electrode to the workpiece?",
    answers: ["To prevent the deposition of tungsten inclusions in the weld metal.",
    "Because the open circuit voltage (no-load voltage) is quite high and the arc can be struck simply by bringing the electrode close to the workpiece surface.",
    "Because the tungsten electrode can stick tightly to the workpiece, and when trying to separate it from the workpiece, the welder may damage the torch.",
    "Because a high short circuit current can destroy the tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why in TIG welding the arc must be opened without touching the electrode to the workpiece?",
    answers: ["Because the open circuit voltage (no-load voltage) is quite high and the arc can be struck simply by bringing the electrode close to the workpiece surface.",
    "Because the tungsten electrode can stick tightly to the workpiece, and when trying to separate it from the workpiece, the welder may damage the torch.",
    "To avoid contamination of the tungsten electrode tip by the base metal.",
    "Because a high short circuit current can destroy the tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What range of base metal thickness is most suitable for submerged arc welding?",
    answers: ["Between 0.5 and 2 mm.",
    "Between 2 and 4 mm.",
    "Between 3 and 6 mm.",
    "Between 5 and 50 mm and thicker."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In oxyacetylene welding, the cause of a lack of fusion in the roots can be:",
    answers: ["a too small root opening;",
    "a too high oxygen flow rate;",
    "a too low welding speed;",
    "a too short torch-to-work distance."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In oxyacetylene welding, the cause of a lack of fusion in the roots can be:",
    answers: ["a too high oxygen flow rate;",
    "a too thick filler metal rod;",
    "a too low welding speed;",
    "a too short torch-to-work distance."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In oxyacetylene welding, the cause of a lack of fusion in the roots can be:",
    answers: ["a too high oxygen flow rate;",
    "a too low welding speed;",
    "a too short torch-to-work distance;",
    "a too small welding torch tip."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Welded metal will be cooled at high rates as it receives a more concentrated heat input.",
    "Only carbon steel can be welded.",
    "It is difficult to control the chemical composition of weld metal. A change in welding variables, especially arc voltage, can adversely affect the weld metal composition.",
    "It is not suitable for extreme conditions (e.g., winds)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of SAW welding?",
    answers: ["Well suited for a wide variety of commonly used metals and alloys.",
    "Virtually no edge preparation is required for materials less than 12 mm thick.",
    "Fluxes for SAW do not need any special treatment (e.g., redrying).",
    "Welding in the overhead position is possible, provided that special devices and accessories are used to maintain the flux."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of these gases is used in the plasma cutting process?",
    answers: ["Compressed air.",
    "Acetylene.",
    "Oxygen.",
    "LPG."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of soldering over (fusion) welding:",
    answers: ["It can perform any type of joint (butt, angle, lap and others).",
    "More heat (because it is a slower process) but lower temperature are required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "It is possible to undo the union, reheating the joint.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of (fusion) welding over soldering:",
    answers: ["Greater strength under high service temperatures (maximum allowed temperature for the weld is the same as for the base metal).",
    "Ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning).",
    "Its application is simple in case of large areas joint.",
    "Minor: operating time, energy consumption, modification of the metal structure, cooling stress and deformation (fewer residual stress problems)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding resistance welding (RW) processes, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The resistance welding processes are: resistance spot welding; seam welding; projection welding; friction welding.",
    "The resistance seam welding is achieved by placing spaced lugs on the disc to avoid continuous stitches.",
    "Resistance welding represents a group of processes that use heat generated by resistance to current flow, combined with the localized application of pressure to join components.",
    "The RW uses the heat generated on the resistance between the electrodes and the surfaces of the metal to be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the consequence of insufficient flux layer height in submerged arc welding (SAW)?",
    answers: ["The arc can “go out” over the flux layer.",
    "The penetration can be reduced.",
    "The risk of generating some defects is low, as the slag is what protects the weld pool.",
    "The entire flux will be melted increasing the transfer of alloying elements from the flux to the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the consequence of insufficient flux layer height in submerged arc welding (SAW)?",
    answers: ["The penetration can be reduced.",
    "There may be a lack of flux for the formation of the slag layer on the bead.",
    "The risk of generating some defects is low, as the slag is what protects the weld pool.",
    "The entire flux will be melted increasing the transfer of alloying elements from the flux to the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the limitations of electrical resistance spot and seam welding is:",
    answers: ["Low repeatability and reliability of weld properties.",
    "These are slow processes.",
    "Limitation of maximum sheet thickness.",
    "A well-trained operator is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The tungsten electrode that has the lowest current capacity is:",
    answers: ["EWP.",
    "EWTH-1.",
    "EWTH-2.",
    "EWZr."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"As per ISO 6947, ASME Section IX and AWS A3.0, there are four main welding positions. What are they?",
    answers: ["Flat, Tilted, Vertical and Overhead.",
    "Flat, Vertical Up, Vertical Down, and Overhead.",
    "Flat, Horizontal, Vertical and Overhead.",
    "Flat, Horizontal, Out of Position and Overhead."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following processes uses tungsten electrodes?",
    answers: ["131",
    "12",
    "311",
    "14"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following processes uses tungsten electrodes?",
    answers: ["131",
    "12",
    "311",
    "141"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following processes uses tungsten electrodes?",
    answers: ["131",
    "12",
    "311",
    "15"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What happens when you change the welding technique from pushing (forehand) to pulling (backhand)?",
    answers: ["The weld becomes wider.",
    "The penetration increases.",
    "The deposition rate goes down.",
    "The penetration decreases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A very narrow and deep but (groove) weld produced by the SAW process will increase the risk of:",
    answers: ["undercuts;",
    "a reduction of tensile strength towards the thinnest thickness;",
    "slag inclusions (making it difficult for the slag to float to the weld pool surface);",
    "poor finishing of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can an excessive flow rate of shielding gas cause in the GTAW (TIG welding) process?",
    answers: ["Cooling of the tungsten electrode and hence an increase in arc voltage.",
    "Cooling of the tungsten electrode and therefore a reduction in thermionic emission.",
    "A turbulence and contamination of the deposited metal.",
    "Crater formation in the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why does the protective cap on a gas cylinder have openings?",
    answers: ["For ventilation.",
    "Openings in the cover are used to lift the cylinder.",
    "For inspection purposes.",
    "To make it lighter."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What type of hose is best suited to transport argon and helium gases to the GTAW (TIG welding) torch?",
    answers: ["Rubber.",
    "Plastic.",
    "Transparent rubber",
    "Rubberized Fabric."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A cause of too small nuggets in electrical resistance spot welding can be (maintaining other parameters properly regulated and constant):",
    answers: ["The surface area of the electrode tip is too small.",
    "The welding time may have been too short.",
    "The current is too low.",
    "The welding voltage is too low."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A cause of too small nuggets in electrical resistance spot welding can be (maintaining other parameters properly regulated and constant):",
    answers: ["The surface area of the electrode tip is too small.",
    "The current is too low.",
    "Welding force (pressure) may have been too high.",
    "The welding voltage is too low."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A cause of too small nuggets in electrical resistance spot welding can be (maintaining other parameters properly regulated and constant):",
    answers: ["The surface area of the electrode tip is too small.",
    "The current is too low.",
    "The welding voltage is too low.",
    "Welding points are very close to each other (shunt effect)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The tungsten electrode tip wears out quickly in TIG welding because of:",
    answers: ["an excessively high voltage for the electrode size;",
    "a high flow rate of shielding gas;",
    "the use of thoria-doped electrodes in AC welding;",
    "an excessive torch tilt."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following is an advantage of using mixtures containing inert and active gases (Ar+O2, Ar+CO2, Ar+ O2+CO2) over the use of the pure CO2:",
    answers: ["weld metal with better properties;",
    "metallurgical treatment of the weld metal to improve mechanical properties;",
    "improved weld geometry (less convexity);",
    "a possibility of producing metal transfer with larger droplet size."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The EWTh-2 electrode colour code is:",
    answers: ["brown;",
    "blue;",
    "yellow;",
    "red."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The no-load voltage of the Constant Current type welding power source is limited. What is the reason?",
    answers: ["Too high no-load voltage can produce uncontrollable welding current.",
    "Due to limitations imposed by the mains input voltage.",
    "A too high no-load voltage produces a too long arc (with a too high voltage).",
    "Because it is required by the standards for safety reasons."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which welding process is easier to apply?",
    answers: ["Plasma welding.",
    "Electron beam welding.",
    "Laser welding.",
    "Explosion welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tungsten electrodes are used for which of the following processes?",
    answers: ["131",
    "12",
    "311",
    "142"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Oxy-acetylene cutting of two or more layers of metal is difficult because:",
    answers: ["the top sheet melts much faster than others;",
    "a great deal of oxygen is required;",
    "there is an air space between the metal surfaces;",
    "this cutting process is not suitable for thick sections."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "},
    {
    question:"The interpass temperature during welding of austenitic stainless steel:",
    answers: ["should always be controlled for thick materials;",
    "should only be controlled for very thin plates;",
    "should always be equal to the preheat temperature and kept below 150 - 180 °C.",
    "should always be kept below 150 - 180 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the objectives of the different types of Heat Treatments applied to steels:",
    answers: ["to increase grain size;",
    "the removal of stresses (from uneven cooling, mechanical work or other causes);",
    "to allow the diffusion of O2 to the external environment, reducing the residual O2 content;",
    "to eliminate porosity."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the objectives of the different types of Heat Treatments applied to steels:",
    answers: ["to increase grain size;",
    "to increase or decrease the hardness of micro-constituents;",
    "to allow the diffusion of O2 to the external environment, reducing the residual O2 content;",
    "to eliminate porosity."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the objectives of the different types of Heat Treatments applied to steels:",
    answers: ["to increase grain size;",
    "to provoke precipitation hardening;",
    "to allow the diffusion of O2 to the external environment, reducing the residual O2 content;",
    "to eliminate porosity."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hardness is a measure of resistance to: ",
    answers: ["corrosion;",
    "penetration;",
    "machinability;",
    "material removal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which property determines the ability of a material to withstand surface indentation (localized plastic deformation)?",
    answers: ["Hardness.",
    "Density.",
    "Strength.",
    "Toughness."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Tensile test gives information about:",
    answers: ["impact properties of the material;",
    "corrosion resistance of the material;",
    "elasticity of the material;",
    "strength of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Tensile test gives information about:",
    answers: ["impact properties of the material;",
    "corrosion resistance of the material;",
    "elasticity of the material;",
    "ductility of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which kind of material would you consider a steel with 0,16%C and approximately 0,3%Mo (e.g., 16Mo3)?",
    answers: ["Unalloyed steel.",
    "Micro alloyed steel.",
    "Low alloyed steel.",
    "High alloyed steel."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Decreasing the residual stress is useful for preventing the:",
    answers: ["Hydrogen cracks;",
    "coarse-grained HAZ;",
    "porosity;",
    "lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Decreasing the residual stress is useful for preventing the:",
    answers: ["lamellar tearing;",
    "coarse-grained HAZ;",
    "porosity;",
    "lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Decreasing the residual stress is useful for preventing the:",
    answers: ["reheat cracking;",
    "coarse-grained HAZ;",
    "porosity;",
    "lack of fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "eliminating sources of hydrogen (e.g., redrying covered electrodes, cleaning joint preparations, ...);",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "using the TIG (GTAW) or MIG/MAG (GMAW) processes in preference to welding with a covered electrode (MMA/SMAW);",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "increasing the heat input;",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "applying preheating;",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "applying immediate post-heating (≈150 - 250 ° C for 1 - 2 hours) thus given time to hydrogen to “bake out” of the material;",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "applying local stress relief post-heating (which also promotes the release of diffusible hydrogen);",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "maintaining the interpass temperature no less than the preheating temperature;",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "ensuring that the time delay between weld runs is minimized (in order to maintain the interpass temperature high);",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "reducing the cooling rate by using heat blankets;",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "reducing the degree of restriction of the joint members;",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hydrogen cracking can be avoided by:",
    answers: ["keeping the interpass temperature low;",
    "using the back stepping technique (serves as a type of stress relieving);",
    "using low welding currents (thus reducing heat input);",
    "using high welding speeds (thus reducing heat input)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What are the parameters of a normal preheating for non-alloy steels?",
    answers: ["Heating between 20 °C and 250 °C during 1 hour.",
    "Heating with 100 °C several times.",
    "Heating between 20 °C and 250 °C.",
    "Heating above 450 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Inconel is a trade name for:",
    answers: ["a titanium alloy;",
    "a copper alloy;",
    "a duplex steel;",
    "a nickel alloy."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which welding processes are used for welding of titanium?",
    answers: ["MMA(SMAW) and MAG welding.",
    "MMA(SMAW) and FCAW.",
    "MIG welding and TIG welding.",
    "MIG welding and FCAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Aluminium alloys can be subdivided in:",
    answers: ["heat treatable alloys and non-heat treatable alloys;",
    "wrought alloys and cast alloys;",
    "alloys to be preheated and alloys, which do not need preheating;",
    "ferritic alloys and austenitic alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Aluminium alloys can be subdivided in:",
    answers: ["hardenable by cold deformation and hardenable by heat treatments;",
    "wrought alloys and cast alloys;",
    "alloys to be preheated and alloys, which do not need preheating;",
    "ferritic alloys and austenitic alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Aluminium alloys can be subdivided in:",
    answers: ["alloys with good weldability by fusion welding and alloys non-weldable by fusion welding;",
    "wrought alloys and cast alloys;",
    "alloys to be preheated and alloys, which do not need preheating;",
    "ferritic alloys and austenitic alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"After welding of stainless steels, the best way to improve the corrosion resistance of the welded joints is:",
    answers: ["painting;",
    "peening;",
    "post weld heat treatment;",
    "pickling."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is a disadvantage of the Charpy test? ",
    answers: ["Test results are not accurate.",
    "Only notch toughness is determined.",
    "Test results are not recordable.",
    "This test is time consuming."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The Brinell hardness test uses a:",
    answers: ["diamond shaped indenter to penetrate the workpiece surface.",
    "sharp blow to force the indenter into the workpiece surface.",
    "round ball which is forced into the workpiece surface.",
    "prismatic indenter and a gradually applied load."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which test is used to determine if a steel could withstand sudden blows at low temperatures?",
    answers: ["Impact test.",
    "Fatigue test.",
    "Tensile test.",
    "Hardness test."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Calculating the percentage of elongation of a specimen in a tensile test will determine:",
    answers: ["material elastic deformation;",
    "material plasticity;",
    "material ductility;",
    "permissible material strain."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The Izod impact test measures:",
    answers: ["hardness of material;",
    "tensile strength of material.",
    "elastic strength of material;",
    "toughness of material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which test gives the most information of the impact or notch toughness of a metal?",
    answers: ["Rockwell test.",
    "Tensile test.",
    "Izod test.",
    "Fatigue test."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is NOT a purpose of post-heating?",
    answers: ["Prevent hydrogen induced cracking.",
    "Help to reduce residual stresses.",
    "Help to reduce preheat temperature.",
    "Help to reduce heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is a weld nick-break test done? ",
    answers: ["To prove weld metal mechanical properties.",
    "To look for hydrogen induced cracks.",
    "To check the internal quality of a weld with regard to porosity, lack of fusion, slag inclusions.",
    "It is a notch bend test, i.e more rigorous bend test. "],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The effect of low stress over a long period of time at elevated temperatures defines:",
    answers: ["fatigue;",
    "creep;",
    "elongation;",
    "degradation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding post-heating of a steel welded joint, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["It allows the diffusion of O2 to the external environment, reducing the residual O2 content;",
    "It allows the diffusion of N2 to the external environment, reducing the residual N2 content;",
    "It aims to increase the weld metal ductility;",
    "It allows the diffusion of H2 to the external environment, reducing the residual H2 content."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The degree of resistance to penetration a material will indicate:",
    answers: ["the toughness of the material;",
    " the impact resistance of the material;",
    "the easiness of the material removal;",
    "the hardness of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following cannot be obtained by the metallographic examination?",
    answers: ["Permanent records of results.",
    "Determination of grain size.",
    "Determination of grain structure.",
    "Evaluation of mechanical properties."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How should a metallographic examination specimen be cut? ",
    answers: ["Using an abrasive water-cooled wheel.",
    "Using plasma cutting (to get a smoother cut surface).",
    "Using a metallic band saw.",
    "Using an oxy-gas cutting torch."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"While viewing a metallographic sample of low carbon steel, the dark lines seen would be separating the grains of:",
    answers: ["cementite and pearlite;",
    "ferrite and cementite;",
    "austenite and martensite;",
    "ferrite and pearlite."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which material requires the least amount of heat input for welding? ",
    answers: ["Mild steel.",
    "Aluminium.",
    "Stainless steel.",
    "Copper."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"With regards to the preheating procedure, the welding inspector should:",
    answers: ["assure that the entire material thickness has been heated to a uniform temperature;",
    "assure that the just weld joint edges have been heated to a uniform temperature;",
    "assure that the entire material thickness has been heated to a uniform temperature, thus measuring the preheat temperature 30 - 50 cm away from the weld joint.",
    "measure the preheat temperature on the same side of the heating source application; "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following affirmations regarding the density of the carbon steel ferrite and austenite is correct?",
    answers: ["The ferrite density is 2% higher than the austenite density.",
    "The austenite density is 2% higher than the ferrite density.",
    "The ferrite density and the austenite density are the same, because they are made of the same element, namely iron.",
    "There is no meaning to compare the ferrite density and the austenite density, because the ferrite and the austenite exist withing different temperature interval."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How the difference between the ferrite and austenite densities can influence the residual stresses in a carbon steel weldment?",
    answers: ["There is no austenite in the carbon steel at room temperature, thus there is no austenite density influence on residual stresses.",
    "The density difference between the ferrite and austenite is less than 2%, thereby its influence on residual stresses in the weldment is negligible.",
    "\"Because a higher density of the ferrite, the weld metal volume reduces during the \"\"austenite to ferrite\"\" transformation.\"",
    "\"Because of the austenite high density, the weld metal volume increases during the \"\"austenite to ferrite\"\" transformation.\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What weld defect may be caused by the absorption of hydrogen by the weld pool liquid metal during welding of carbon steels?",
    answers: ["Porosity.",
    "Hot cracking.",
    "Cold cracking.",
    "Non-metallic inclusions."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What does creep strain depend on?",
    answers: ["Stress level.",
    "Time and temperature.",
    "Stress level and time.",
    "Stress level, exposure time and temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Within three factors that determine the degradation of the steel and creep deformation (stress level, time and temperature):",
    answers: ["the temperature acts more effectively than the exposure time;",
    "the exposure time acts more effectively than the temperature;",
    "the exposure time acts more effectively than the tension level;",
    "the temperature and the exposure time act in the same way."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How, by analysing the fracture surface of the Charpy test specimen, can you know that it was broken at the ductile-brittle transition temperature?",
    answers: ["If all surface has a brittle appearance.",
    "If all surface has a rough appearance with deformation of the material.",
    "If the surface presents 50% of brittle appearance and 50% of rough appearance with deformation of the material.",
    "If the surface presents 50% of brittle appearance and 50% of rough appearance with deformation of the material, and this ductile area expands from the centre."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How shall hot cracking be prevented in welding of austenitic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["By preheating.",
    "By low heat input.",
    "By postweld heating.",
    "By postweld heat treatment."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"\"The symbol \"\"a\"\" in connection with fillet welds means:\"",
    answers: ["leg length;",
    "actual throat;",
    "effective throat;",
    "theoretical throat."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"For a concave fillet weld, which throat dimensions are the same?",
    answers: ["Theoretical and effective.",
    "Actual and effective.",
    "Theoretical and actual.",
    "Hypothetical and effective."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"\"What is understood under the term \"\"fatigue of a material\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["Material strength reduction (aging) due to long-term static loading.",
    "Material strength reduction (aging followed by buckling) due to long-term compressive loading.",
    "Gradual propagation of an initial crack to its critical size due to cyclic variation of localized compressive stress.",
    "Gradual propagation of an initial crack to its critical size due to cyclic variation of localized tensile stress."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the fillet weld leg?",
    answers: ["The distance from the joint root to the toe of a convex fillet weld.",
    "The distance from the joint root to the toe of a concave fillet weld.",
    "The shortest distance between the root and the face of the weld.",
    "The greatest distance between the root and the face of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the fillet weld leg?",
    answers: ["The leg of the largest right triangle inscribed within the cross-sectional area of the concave fillet weld.",
    "The distance from the joint root to the toe of a concave fillet weld.",
    "The shortest distance between the root and the face of the weld.",
    "The greatest distance between the root and the face of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the bevel angle?",
    answers: ["\"It is the total angle between the parts that will be joined by a weld with \"\"U\"\" edge preparation.\"",
    "\"It is the total angle between the parts that will be joined by a weld with \"\"V\"\" edge preparation. \"",
    "\"It is the total angle between the parts that will be joined by a weld with \"\"X\"\" edge preparation.\"",
    "It is the angle formed between the bevelled edge of a part and a plane perpendicular to the surface of that part."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the groove angle?",
    answers: ["It is half the angle between the prepared edges of the parts to be joined.",
    "It is the total included angle between the prepared edges of the parts to be joined.",
    "\"It is the total angle between the parts that will be joined by a weld with \"\"U\"\" edge preparation.\"",
    "It is the angle formed between the bevelled edge of a part and a plane perpendicular to the surface of that part."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the bevel and groove angles it can be said that:",
    answers: ["the bevel angle is always twice the groove angle;",
    "the groove angle is always twice the bevel angle;",
    "the groove angle can be equal to the bevel angle of one of the members to be joined;",
    "the groove angle cannot be equal to the bevel angle."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the theoretical (design) throat?",
    answers: ["The distance from the beginning of the joint root perpendicular to the hypotenuse of the largest right triangle that can be inscribed within the cross section of a fillet weld.",
    "The shortest distance between the root and the face of the weld, considering all reinforcements.",
    "The shortest distance between the root and the face of the weld, minus any reinforcement.",
    "The greatest distance between the root and the face of the weld, minus any reinforcement."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the effective throat?",
    answers: ["The greatest distance between the root and the face of the weld, minus any reinforcement.",
    "The shortest distance between the root and the face of the weld, considering all reinforcements.",
    "The minimum distance minus any convexity between the weld root and the face of a fillet weld.",
    "The greatest distance between the root and the face of the weld, considering all reinforcements."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the actual throat?",
    answers: ["The minimum distance between the weld root and the face of a fillet weld.",
    "The greatest distance between the root and the face of a fillet weld.",
    "The shortest distance between the root and the face of the weld, minus any reinforcement.",
    "The greatest distance between the root and the face of the weld, minus any reinforcement."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following testing methods enables to draw a conclusion on material behaviour under changing loads?",
    answers: ["CTOD cracking test.",
    "Fatigue test.",
    "Impact test.",
    "Tensile test."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When a load is applied to a welded joint:",
    answers: ["it gives rise to residual stresses that add to the external loading;",
    "it always increases the resulting stress (residual stress + load stress);",
    "by their nature residual stresses are always greater than loading stresses;",
    "the resulting stress will depend on both the residual stress and the external loading."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A fatigue failure of a weldment may occur:",
    answers: ["Under very high static loading;",
    "Under any type of loading as long as the service temperature is low;",
    "Under any type of loading as long as the service temperature is high;",
    "After a large number of cycles of loading."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the difference between deformation and distortion of the welded joint?",
    answers: ["Although in welding, these terms are generally used synonymously, it's more correct to consider distortion as the result of the deformation process.",
    "Distortion is an elastic (reversible) change of the body shape, while deformation is a permanent change in the body shape.",
    "Distortion is the first (elastic or reversible) phase of the body deformation process.",
    "Deformation is the first (elastic or reversible) phase of the body distortion process."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the limitations of the Impact Test with regard to the study of the brittle fracture mechanism of metals:",
    answers: ["This method is suitable for low temperatures only, as its results at high temperatures do not correspond to the actual toughness of the material;",
    "Test results depend on the size of the pendulum requiring certain correlations;",
    "The notch is characterized by a different state of stress as compared to the crack;",
    "It has no generally accepted impact method, so many methods like Charpy, Izod, and others are used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the limitations of the Impact Test with regard to the study of the brittle fracture mechanism of metals:",
    answers: ["This method is suitable for low temperatures only, as its results at high temperatures do not correspond to the actual toughness of the material;",
    "Test results depend on the size of the pendulum requiring certain correlations;",
    "The test is dynamic, but it is known that the load application rate influences the fracture toughness: higher loading rate, lower toughness value;",
    "It has no generally accepted impact method, so many methods like Charpy, Izod, and others are used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the limitations of the Impact Test with regard to the study of the brittle fracture mechanism of metals:",
    answers: ["This method is suitable for low temperatures only, as its results at high temperatures do not correspond to the actual toughness of the material;",
    "Test results depend on the size of the pendulum requiring certain correlations;",
    "At high loading rates, dislocations do not follow the energy release, and do not undergo plastic deformation, which favours a lower tenacity value;",
    "It has no generally accepted impact method, so many methods like Charpy, Izod, and others are used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the limitations of the Impact Test with regard to the study of the brittle fracture mechanism of metals:",
    answers: ["This method is suitable for low temperatures only, as its results at high temperatures do not correspond to the actual toughness of the material;",
    "Test results depend on the size of the pendulum requiring certain correlations;",
    "In many cases, the results of the Impact Test require correlations for application in integrity assessment;",
    "It has no generally accepted impact method, so many methods like Charpy, Izod, and others are used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the limitations of the Impact Test with regard to the study of the brittle fracture mechanism of metals:",
    answers: ["This method is suitable for low temperatures only, as its results at high temperatures do not correspond to the actual toughness of the material;",
    "Test results depend on the size of the pendulum requiring certain correlations;",
    "Small dimensions of the standard specimen (55 x 10 x 10 mm) are unsuitable for high thicknesses;",
    "It has no generally accepted impact method, so many methods like Charpy, Izod, and others are used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"to penetrate into discontinuities of the workpiece;",
    answers: ["to absorb the penetrant from discontinuities and to provide a white background;",
    "to clean the surface of the workpiece to be tested.",
    "2",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"cast materials;",
    answers: ["porous materials;",
    "carbon steel.",
    "2",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"Microwaves and beta rays;",
    answers: ["Alpha rays and infrared rays;",
    "X-rays and gamma rays.",
    "3",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"Questioning those responsible for welding, including the welder(s) about the material used.",
    answers: ["Such verification is unnecessary as the material must be released from the warehouse in accordance with the job documentation.",
    "Comparing mechanical properties of the material used with those of the material indicated in the project.",
    "0",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"non-metallic inclusions;",
    answers: ["cracks that have propagated to the surface;",
    "internal porosity.",
    "2",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"surface-breaking defects;",
    answers: ["Internal hydrogen cracks;",
    "Solidification cracks only.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"it does not need special equipment or specific training;",
    answers: ["it discovers all kinds of internal discontinuities;",
    "it promptly discovers surface imperfections.",
    "3",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"Binoculars;",
    answers: ["Magnifying glass;",
    "Mirror.",
    "3",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"detect weld metal porosity;",
    answers: ["measure the geometric parameters of the weld;",
    "evaluate the density of the material.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"detect internal cracks in welded joint;",
    answers: ["measure the geometric parameters of the weld;",
    "evaluate the density of the material.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"detect internal inclusions in the weld metal;",
    answers: ["measure the geometric parameters of the weld;",
    "evaluate the density of the material.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"Visual inspection.",
    answers: ["Radiography inspection.",
    "Ultrasonic testing.",
    "2",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"Organization of welding operations.",
    answers: ["Selection of qualified welders to fulfil certain welding tasks.",
    "Assistance to welding engineers in their daily duties.",
    "0",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"Engineering experience.",
    answers: ["Non-destructive testing experience.",
    "General knowledge of the welding processes.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"verify, witness and understand all welding related activities in fabrication.",
    answers: ["calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "assist to welding engineers in their daily duties.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"verify the adequacy of information on NDT reports (VT, PT, MT, RT, UT) for conventional techniques",
    answers: ["calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "assist to welding engineers in their daily duties.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"verify data and adequacy of material certificates (base and filler materials).",
    answers: ["specify, supervise and manage welding personnel and related personnel needs and competences/skills.",
    "assist to welding engineers in their daily duties.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"verify identification and traceability of the materials during the fabrication process.",
    answers: ["calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "understand and supervise the proper use of equipment and means needed for the construction.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"verify the compliance of raw materials and consumables against the applicable standards, codes and specifications.",
    answers: ["calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "supervise implementation and monitor subcontracting activities.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"verify the implementation of the WPS in production for conventional applications.",
    answers: ["supervise and monitor the welding personnel and related personnel needs and competences/skills.",
    "assist to welding engineers in their daily duties.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"verify the implementation of PWHT specifications in production.",
    answers: ["understand and implement working instructions.",
    "understand, implement, supervise and monitor heat treatments.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"witness welder approval tests including testing of the specimens or test coupons.",
    answers: ["calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "understand and implement Welding Procedures needed for the construction.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"witness production test coupons.",
    answers: ["specify, supervise and manage welding personnel and related personnel needs and competences/skills.",
    "implement, monitor and control corrective actions to solve welded construction non-conformances.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"read and understand an Inspection Testing Plan.",
    answers: ["calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "understand and supervise the proper use of equipment and means needed for the construction.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"read and understand the construction drawings in relation to inspection activities.",
    answers: ["calculate weldment geometrical parameters.",
    "supervise implementation and monitor subcontracting activities.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""
    },
    {
    question:"report any of the IWI-B actions to a qualified supervisor.",
    answers: ["supervise and monitor the welding personnel and related personnel needs and competences/skills.",
    "assist to welding engineers in their daily duties.",
    "1",
    "3"],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:""}]
    
    ;